Cosentino Fernando

Systems Analyst - Software Developer

Mar del plata, Argentina - +54 9 223 593 4366 - feracosentino@gmail.com - cosentinodev.vercel.app

Systems Analyst and Software Developer with experience in building full-stack web applications using Django and Flask, complemented by frontend expertise in React.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hidráulica MP - Web developer & Consultant - May 2024 - Currently.

- Development and maintenance of the company website and a stock and sales management system.
- Technology consulting to optimize commercial operations.
- Web development using React for the frontend.
- Nevelopment of an administrative application with Django.
- Use of PostgreSQL as a relational database.
- Neployment of the application on Vercel.

Simuladores en Red - Network Technician - Dec 2018 - May 2021.

- Network configuration, monitoring, troubleshooting, and maintenance.
- Maintenance and repair of hardware components.
- Remote technical support.

EDUCATION

HILET Instituto Argentino de la Empresa - Systems Analyst Technician - Apr 2021 - May 2024.

- Data Structures & Algorithms, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, etc.
- * Hardware Architecture, Networks and Communications, etc.
- Business Economy, Systems and Organizations, etc.
- Agile project management with Scrum.

Universidad Nacional de Mar del Plata - Mechanical Engineering - Ago 2011 - Dec 2016

- Sained an understanding of advanced mathematics, physics, and thermodynamics concepts applied to engineering problem-solving.
- Experienced in experimental techniques and the use of specialized software tools for creating and analyzing mechanical models.

KNOWLEDGE & SKILLS

- Backend Languages: Python [Django, Flask, FastAPI], C# [.NET], PHP [Codeigniter], Java [Spring Boot].
- ORMs: SQLAlchemy, Django ORM, Dapper, Mapper.
- Database Managers: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server.
- Architectures: RESTFul API, MVC, MTV
- Web development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, JWT, Bootstrap, ChakraUI and frontend framework React.
- Infrastructure: Linux systems (end-user & server oriented). Docker and orchestration with Portainer.
- Version control with Git and GitHub.

CERTIFICATIONS

Global Mentoring Ing. Ubaldo Acosta [Udemy] - Universidad Python - Dic 2023 - Nov 2024.

- Python Programming, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) and Database & File Management.
- GUI Development with Tkinter and PySide.
- Web development using Django and Flask.

LANGUAGES

- Spanish [Native]
- English [B1]